(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-08T22:00:10.956421",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.8-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
火の用心じゃ〜！
Watch out for fire~!
あらあら〜？ めらめら〜？
Oh my~? Blazing away~?
熱千めらー！！
Achiha Mera~!!
ホロライブ アソビ★まわり隊！
hololive Asobi★Mawaritai!
ご利益担当の火消し屋サラマンダー
The blessing-bringing firefighter salamander,
熱千めらなのじゃー！
I'm Achiha Mera!
みなさん！ はじめまして！！
Nice to meet you all!
2026年9月24日にホロライブからデビューした
Having debuted from hololive on September 24, 2026,
ピカピカの新人VTuberなのじゃ〜！
I'm a brand-spanking-new rookie VTuber~!
今日は わしの自己紹介動画を撮っていこうと思うのじゃ！
Today, I'm going to record my self-introduction video!
わしのこと「どんな子かな〜？」とか気になってたり
For anyone wondering "What kind of girl is she?",
「人間じゃないの？」「なんで髪の毛燃えてるの？」とか
or asking "Isn't she human?" or "Why is her hair on fire?",
ホロライブのオーディションを受けた時の話とかもしようかなって思ってるので
or even about when I auditioned for hololive...
この動画を見て わしのこと
I'd be super happy if you watch this video...
いっぱい知ってくれたら 嬉しいのじゃ！
...and get to know a whole lot about me!
ということで！ 動画スタート！！
So with that, let's start the video!!
名前は 熱千めら
My name is Achiha Mera.
「ねっせん」じゃないのじゃ！ 「あちち」って読むのじゃ！
It's not "Nessen"! It's read "Achichi"!
「千度の熱」と書いて「熱千（あちち）」
Written with "a thousand degrees of heat", it's "Achichi"!
良い名前なのじゃ！
It's a great name!
そして「めら」 メラメラの「めら」なのじゃ！
And "Mera" comes from the flaring "mera-mera"!
火が燃えてる時の
It's like an onomatopoeia or sound effect...
オノマトペ？ 擬音？ みたいなやつなのじゃ！
...for when a fire is blazing up!
漢字がちょっと分かりづらいのと あと辞書で一発で出てこないので
The kanji is a bit tricky, and it doesn't pop up right away on keyboards,
めら組のお主らは
so for everyone in the Mera Crew,
「熱千」をスマホとかで辞書登録みたいなのができたはずじゃから
you can register "Achiha" into your phone's dictionary,
それで辞書登録していつでも熱千を呼び出せるようにしてほしいのじゃ！
so please register it so you can type "Achiha" anytime!
そして お主らが気になってるであろう種族！
And next, the species you're probably curious about!
わしは サラマンダーなのじゃ！
I am a salamander!
見て このツノ ツノ
Look at these horns, horns!
あと 尻尾なのじゃ〜！
And here's my tail~!
どうかのお？ 可愛いかのぉ？
How does it look? Isn't it cute?
サラマンダーとは 火を司る精霊らしいのじゃ！
Salamanders are spirits that govern fire!
わしの髪の毛からもね こうやって炎が出ておるじゃろ？
Flames come out of my hair like this too, see?
これはね 体内の熱をね どっかから出さないとね わしが火を噴いちゃってね
If I don't vent internal body heat from somewhere, I end up spitting fire,
周りをね 大変なことにしちゃう 火だらけにしちゃうから
and that would cause huge chaos by catching everything on fire,
こうやって髪から出すことでな 火をね 暴発しないようにしておるんじゃ。
so by releasing it from my hair, I keep the fire from erupting.
わし的には正直人間と変わらんくね？ と思ってるところがあって
Honestly, part of me feels like I'm barely any different from humans,
火に強いとは言いつつも 火傷はするのじゃ。
because even though they say I'm heat-resistant, I still get burned.
手とか指とかは火傷しないんじゃけど あの粘膜 粘膜は結構火傷しちゃうから
My hands and fingers don't get burned, but my mucous membranes easily do,
それこそベロとか あったかいさ ココアとか飲む時は
so like my tongue, whenever I drink hot cocoa or something,
ベロ火傷しちゃって 熱くなるのじゃ。
I burn my tongue and it stings like crazy.
あと 炎属性なんじゃが 夏はめちゃくちゃ暑いのじゃ！
Also, I'm fire-elemental, but summers are insanely hot for me!
日本の夏ヤバいのじゃ。湿気とかもあるからかな？
Japanese summers are brutal. Maybe it's the humidity?
ヤバいから 熱中症になるのじゃ熱中症！ サラマンダーなのに！
It's so bad I get heatstroke! Heatstroke! Even though I'm a salamander!
熱中症とか火傷とかそういうのならないようにすればいいのになぁ...
I really wish I were just immune to heatstroke and burns and stuff...
わしはあと火を吹いたりできるのじゃ！
Also, I can breathe fire!
火を吹くところはね デビューした時 あの情報解禁の時に上げてる映像に
As for breathing fire, in the video released when my debut was announced,
火をね 吹いてるねアニメーションがあってね それを見てほしいのじゃ。
there's an animation of me breathing fire, so I want you to watch that!
わしのかっこいいところが見れるかもしれないのじゃ。
You might get to see my cool side.
わしの年齢は415歳！ 長生きなのじゃ〜
My age is 415 years old! I've lived a long life~
生年月日で言うと 1611年の4月16日生まれなのじゃ。
Going by date of birth, I was born on April 16, 1611.
何年何月何日とか言ったんじゃが 厳密には覚えてなくて
I just gave an exact date, but strictly speaking, I don't really remember;
大体 江戸時代だった気がするのじゃ〜
I just vaguely feel like it was around the Edo period~
あとわしは良い子じゃから 415（よいこ）歳ってことにしようと思って
And since I'm a good kid ("yoi-ko" = 4-1-5), I decided to be 415 years old,
415歳ってことにしようと思って
I thought, "Let's go with 415 years old!"
そっから逆算することによって 1611年生まれになったということじゃ。そういうことじゃ。
So by calculating backwards from that, it resulted in being born in 1611! That's how it is.
全部うろ覚えなのじゃ。
It's all a faint memory!
そんな何百年も前のことを覚えてるわけないのじゃ！
There's no way I'd remember things from hundreds of years ago!
まあ大体400歳ぐらいじゃと思って頂ければ良いのかなと思うのじゃ。
Well, I think it's fine if you just think of me as roughly 400 years old.
そして400年前 わしが生まれたての頃何をしていたかと言うと
And as for what I was doing 400 years ago when I was freshly born,
火消しという職業をしていたのじゃ！
I worked as a firefighter!
火消しってのは現代で言うところの消防団みたいな 文字通り火事を消すのじゃ。
A firefighter back then was like today's firefighting brigade, literally putting out fires.
わしはサラマンダーじゃから ある程度火には強くて
Since I'm a salamander, I was somewhat resistant to fire,
だから 火事が大変になってるところにも行って
so I'd rush to sites where fires were raging,
わしがこう率先してね 火を消していくのじゃ。シャシャシャシャシャッて。
and take the initiative putting out flames like swoosh, swoosh, swoosh!
そしてわしは纏持というものをやっていたのじゃ！
And I served as a standard-bearer ("matoi-mochi")!
火消しっていう火を消す人たちがいるじゃろ？
You know how there are firefighters who put out fires?
その中でも その纏っていうね でっかい棒にね なんか付いててね 振るやつがあるのじゃ。
Among them, there's that "matoi"—a huge pole with decorations that you wave around.
それをね 持ってたのじゃ。
I was the one holding that!
当然人間の寿命よりもわしの寿命の方が長いから
Naturally, my lifespan is much longer than a human's,
仲良かった人間たちがみんないなくなっちゃって 「しばらく一人でいるか〜」と思って
so all the humans I was close to were gone, and thinking "Guess I'll live alone for a while~",
その後は山に籠ってたのじゃ。200年ぐらい。
I holed up in the mountains after that. For about 200 years.
山に籠ってる間にしてたこと。
What I did while holed up in the mountains:
寝て 起きて 食べて 寝てたのじゃ。
I slept, woke up, ate, and slept.
200年ぐらいずーっと寝て起きて食べて寝ての生活をしてたのじゃ。
For about 200 years, I just lived a life of sleeping, waking, eating, and sleeping.
山から降りて人間と一緒に暮らし始めてから
Since coming down from the mountain and starting to live with humans,
今まで20年ぐらい人間と共に生活をしてきたのじゃ。
I've been living alongside humans for about 20 years now.
人間20年生っていうことじゃの。
So I guess you could call me a 20-year-old human!
なんでわしが人間として暮らし始めたかという話なんじゃが
As for the story of why I started living with humans:
わしが山で生活していた時にの 山にスマホがね 捨ててあったんじゃよ。
Back when I was living in the mountains, a smartphone had been abandoned there!
「スマホおもれ〜！」と思って触ってたら
Thinking "Smartphones are so cool!", I messed around with it,
わしは匿名掲示板を発見したんじゃよ。
and discovered an anonymous message board.
で 匿名掲示板で「これ会話できるのでは〜！」と思って
And on that board, thinking "Wait, I can chat with people here?!",
そこに書き込みとかをしてたんじゃよ。
I started writing posts there!
そう 人間と話せるの嬉しくて...
Yeah, I was just so happy to be able to talk with humans...
拾ってすぐやり始めたから
Since I started using it right after picking it up,
その何だろう ネットのお作法じゃないけど
like, what do you call it, not quite netiquette,
その空気感みたいなのを全然知らなくて
but I had no idea about the vibe or atmosphere,
何をして良くて何がしちゃダメでみたいな
like what was okay to do and what wasn't,
全然分かんなくて
I didn't understand any of it.
初心者がネットを使いまくって
So with a total beginner using the internet non-stop,
しかもその場所が匿名掲示板とかいう
and on an anonymous message board of all places,
めちゃくちゃ危ない状況になってて
it became an extremely dangerous situation,
自演コメントをしたんじゃよ
and I made a sockpuppet comment.
自分を守るようなコメントをしたんじゃが
I posted a comment trying to defend myself,
そしたら
but then,
自演がバレる系の掲示板だったっぽくて
it turned out to be a board where sockpuppeting gets exposed,
他のスレッドとかにも書き込んでたから
and since I'd posted in other threads too,
そういうので照合して
they cross-referenced that,
IPとかそういうので...
using IPs and stuff...
同一人物ってバレちゃう系のやつで
It was the kind of place where you get exposed as the same person,
ぶっ叩かれたのじゃ
and I got totally bashed!
怖かったー あれ本当に怖かったのじゃ
It was terrifying... That was really terrifying!
な、なんでそんな言う！？みたいなこといっぱい言われて
They said so many things like, "Why would you say that?!"
わしが人間について詳しくないから
Because I didn't know much about humans,
なんでそれがダメか分かんないじゃろうなと思って
I thought, "I guess that's why I didn't get why it was wrong,"
人間について知りたくて山から降りたのじゃ
and wanting to learn about humans, I came down from the mountain.
人間の父と母に拾ってもらって 人間として育ててもらったのじゃ
A human mother and father took me in, and they raised me as a human.
学校も行ったのじゃ
I even went to school!
幼稚園とかから通って
Going all the way from kindergarten,
人間社会で人間とはなんたるかを学んで
and learning what it means to be human in human society,
人間20年生！
I'm a 20th-year human!
人間20年生なのじゃ
I've been a human for 20 years!
じゃから これからわしが「父」とか「母」とか そういうワードを使う時は
So whenever I use words like "father" or "mother" from now on,
わしのことを育ててくれた人間の「父・母」を指すと思って欲しいのじゃ
please know that I'm referring to the human "father and mother" who raised me.
今ホロライブに入るまでの人生 サラマンダー生みたいなのをまとめた
And summarizing my life before joining hololive, my "salamander life,"
「episode 0」という動画がアップロードされていると思うので
a video titled "episode 0" should be uploaded,
もっと気になるよっていう人間たちは
so any humans who want to know more,
わしのその動画をご覧...
please go take a...
ください！のじゃ〜！
look at it! Ja~!
性格発表しちゃうか！
Shall I announce my personality!
わしは 素直で優しい とっても良い子なのじゃ
I am an honest, kind, and very good girl!
自認ね
In my own opinion, that is.
自認ね！自認ね！
Self-proclaimed! Self-proclaimed!
マネちゃんと初めて会った時
And you know, when I first met my manager,
顔合わせみたいなのがあったんじゃよ
we had a face-to-face meeting.
その時に自己紹介をするじゃろ？
And you introduce yourself then, right?
その時に「わしは〜 優しくて良い子だと思います！」って言ったのじゃ
At that time, I said, "I think I'm kind and a good girl!"
でもね わし気づいちゃったんじゃがね
But you know, I realized something...
自分で自分のこと優しいって初対面のの人間に言う人って たぶん あんま優しくない！
People who tell someone they just met that they're kind... probably aren't that kind!
わしさー シャワー中に1日反省会するタイプなんじゃが
You see, I'm the type who reflects on my day in the shower,
猛反省したんじゃ
and I reflected on it so hard.
うわー あれ失言だったなぁー
"Ugh, that was such a slip of the tongue..."
別にわざわざ自分から 良い子っていうのは他人から見出されるものであって
"Being a 'good kid' is something other people discover in you,"
自分でしかも初手で 自己開示するものではなかったかなぁー
"not something you're supposed to announce yourself right off the bat..."
と思いながら 髪ワシャワシャって洗ってたのじゃ
I thought as I scrubbed my hair like wash-wash-wash!
どうしよう マネちゃんに「今 わしのことどう思ってる…思いますか」って聞いて
"What if I ask Mane-chan, 'What do you think of me right now?' and she goes,"
「いや いい…まあ良い子なん…どうですかね？ 自分から言うほどじゃないですかね」とか言われたらどうしよう！とか思ってて
"'Well, a g-good... well, a good kid, maybe? Not quite enough to say it yourself, though?' What if she said that?!"
もうしょうがない！しょうがないのじゃ 言ってしまったもんね
Well, it can't be helped! Nothing I can do, I already said it!
本当に良い子！
I really am a good girl!
じゃから 配信とか動画を見て「わしのことを良い子だな」と思ったら
So if you watch my streams or videos and think, "She's such a good girl,"
どの動画にでも良いから「良い子だね」ってコメントを書いて欲しいのじゃ！
please leave a comment saying "You're a good girl" on any video!
そしたらわしは「あ、やっぱりわしの自認は間違ってなかったんじゃ」って自信に繋がるからな！
Because then I'll gain confidence thinking, "Ah, my self-assessment wasn't wrong after all!"
次〜！好きなもの！
Next! Things I like!
好きなもの3つあるから紹介しちゃおうかな
I have three things I like, so let me share them!
好きなもの①
Thing I like number one:
人間！
Humans!
人間って個体差すごぐない！？
Aren't individual differences between humans amazing?!
あれめっちゃ良いなって思うのじゃ！
I think that's so great!
色んな人間と話して来たんじゃが
I've talked to many different humans,
全員違うのじゃ！
and every single one is different!
考え方の癖とか 物事の見え方もだし 喋り方も違うし
Their habits of thinking, their perspectives on things, their way of speaking—
誰と喋ってもおもろいのじゃ！
whoever I talk to, it's so interesting!
わし本当は全人類と 1on1トークしたいのじゃ
Honestly, I want to have a one-on-one talk with all of humanity.
ダメかのお？
Is that not allowed?
喋るのめっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I love chatting so much!
こうやってインターネットを通して お主らとコミュニケーション取るのもすごい嬉しいし
Communicating with you all through the internet like this makes me super happy,
あと わし人間の言葉がめちゃくちゃ好きで
and also, I really love human words,
Twitter(X)を見るのがめちゃくちゃ好きで 特に文字ツイート見るのがめちゃくちゃ好きで
so I love looking at Twitter (X), especially reading text-only tweets!
めら組のツイートとかも見るんじゃが
I look at tweets from the Mera-gumi too,
この人は何を言うかもだし 何を言わないかとかもめっちゃ見てて
and I look closely at not only what people say, but also what they don't say.
「このツイートをするってことは こういうことは思ってそうだけど でもあえてこういうの言わないんじゃないか」とか
Like, "Since they tweeted this, they might be thinking that, but chose not to say it..."
考察するのめちゃくちゃ好きなのじゃ
I absolutely love analyzing that!
Twitterってめちゃくちゃ人間の情報が取れてお得なのじゃ
Twitter is such a bargain because you can gather so much info on humans!
文字じゃない会話も好きでね メンバーと電話するのも好きなのじゃ！
I also like spoken conversations, and I love calling the other members too!
面接めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I really love interviews!
ホロライブのオーディション受けた時も思ったんじゃが
I felt this when I auditioned for hololive too,
面接中って人間めっちゃ構ってくれるんじゃよ
but during an interview, humans pay so much attention to me!
何言っても熱心に聞いてくれるし
Whatever I say, they listen attentively,
しかも場合によっては何人もの人がわしのこと聞いてくれるし 深掘りまでしてくれるのじゃ！
and multiple people listen to me and even dig deeper into my answers!
「それってこういうことですか？」みたいな 「そうなのじゃ！そうなのじゃ！」って思うのじゃ！
Like, "Do you mean it's like this?" and I'm like, "Yes, exactly! Exactly!"
面接 週一でしたい
I want to have an interview once a week!
あれぐらい いっぱい人に構ってもらいたいんじゃ
I just want people to pay that much attention to me!
好きなもの②
Thing I like number two:
ボーカロイド！
Vocaloid!
合成音声大好きなのじゃ！
I love synthetic vocals!
ボカロ曲大好きなのじゃ！
I love Vocaloid songs!
1日中聴いてる
I listen to them all day long.
人間と電話しながらボカロ曲聴きながら作業してるのじゃ これがわしの日常
Calling humans while listening to Vocaloid songs while working. That's my daily routine!
好きなボカロPさん いっぱいいるんじゃけど
There are so many Vocaloid producers I like,
特にツミキさんっていうボカロPの方がめっちゃ好きで
but I especially love a Vocaloid producer named Tsumiki-san!
好きなアルバム一選 「SAKKAC CRAFT」めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
My number one favorite album, I absolutely love "SAKKAC CRAFT"!
めっちゃかっこいいのじゃ！
It's so cool!
わし あれしか聴いてない！
I don't listen to anything else!
あれしか聴いてないっていうのはこれはあれ オタクの嘘
Saying "I don't listen to anything else" is, you know, an otaku lie.
オタクの...誇張の 強調する時に使うやつなんじゃが
An otaku... exaggeration used for emphasis, but...
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
この自己紹介動画さえ見てれば
As long as you've watched this self-introduction video,
まあ 熱千めら 9割ぐらい分かったと言っても
I feel like you could say you understand 90% of Achichi Mera
過言ではないぐらいな内容な気がする
without it really being an exaggeration.
過言か？過言かあ
Or is it? Maybe it is an exaggeration!
楽しんでもらえたなら幸いなのじゃ！
If you enjoyed it, that makes me so happy!
そして最後に 一言！
And lastly, one final thought!
わし 運命を信じてるのじゃ
I believe in fate.
人生ってさ
In life,
その時その時で出会うべき人みたいなのがいるじゃないですか？
aren't there people you're meant to meet at certain points in time?
それが お主らにとってのその時出会うべきだった人が
And for all of you, that person you were meant to meet at this time—
わしじゃったら良いな〜ってすごい思うんじゃよ
I really hope that person turns out to be me.
熱千めらと出会ってから
"Ever since I met Achichi Mera,
すごい毎日楽しくなって
every day has become so much fun,
居場所になったよって
and it has become a place where I belong."
思ってくれる人間が1人でもいっぱいいたら
If there's even one more person who feels that way,
わしはここに来た意味があったなって思うし
then I feel that coming here truly had meaning,
そうなるように これからお主にとっての温かい居場所になることを願って
and wishing to become that warm place for you,
活動していきます！
I will keep going with all my activities!
チャンネル登録とか 高評価とか コメントとか
Through subscribing, leaving likes, and writing comments—
色んな方法でわしのことを応援してくれると とっても嬉しいのじゃ！
I'd be so happy if you could support me in any way you can!
そして デビュー記念ボイスとか デビューにあたっていろんなものが販売中なので
Also, debut commemorative voice packs and various goods are currently on sale,
そちらも興味があったらチェックしてみて欲しいのじゃ！
so please check those out too if you're interested!
ということで 今日の動画はおしまいなのじゃ！
And with that, today's video is coming to an end!
また動画とか配信とか 色んなところでお主と会えると嬉しいのじゃ！
I'd love to see you all again in future videos, streams, and everywhere else!
これからよろしくね！
I look forward to our time together!
ということで！また次の何かでお会いしましょ〜！
So then! Let's meet again next time in whatever comes next!
ばいばいなのじゃ〜！
Bye-bye~!